# SIMON MARIANI

# Software/AI Engineer

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# • Stactics - Data/Al Engineer

Jul 2023 - Present - full-time

At Stactics, I worked as a **consultant** and **product developer**. I developed and refined many skills as I built large **frontend** and **backend applications**. Alongside building complex web-applications, I also **led the deployment** onto cloud platforms using **Docker**, **Kubernetes**, and **GitHub actions**. This included projects focused on **data analysis** and **AI**, where I used real-life data to implement AI solutions in the cloud or embedded. In these projects, I **engaged with clients** and **managed stakeholders**.

# • ViNotion - Research Intern

Nov 2021 - Jul 2022 - full time

I did my master's thesis at ViNotion, which focusses on **computer vision** in an **edge computing** fashion. Here, I worked with real life data from cameras mounted on trucks and took a deep dive into **segmentation networks** and **Out-of-Distribution Detection**. I am proud to say that my **research was <u>published</u>** and I look back upon my time here fondly.

# Blackbear - Consultant

Jan 2022 - Dec 2022 - part time

Blackbear provides a platform where companies can meet freelancing individuals. Here, I did **market research** of which the result became the foundation of their **new products**.

# • Vinea - Programming Camp Coordinator

Jun 2019 – Aug 2020 – part time

I coordinated several programming camps for children between the ages of 9 and 13, where I **managed** and **taught** software skills.

# **EDUCATION**

# University of Amsterdam - MSc Artificial Intelligence

Sep 2020 - Jul 2022

The MSc Artificial Intelligence at the University of Amsterdam is one of the **best in its field**, and I am proud to say that after two years I managed to complete the master's degree **with distinction** and **publish my master's thesis**. The study program is very technical and covers a wide range of fields within AI in depth. This required a high proficiency in **python and math** as well as a high degree of **adaptability and persistence**.

#### • Tsinghua University - Exchange

Aug 2019 - Feb 2020

Tsinghua University is one of the <a href="https://mini.com/highest-ranking-universities-globally">highest-ranking-university in China</a>. During my exchange here, I grew as a software engineer and my adaptability to new environments and techniques was profoundly tested. It also provided me with a unique global perspective on technology and education, as well as many insights into their extensive culture.

# • Utrecht University - BSc Artificial Intelligence

Sep 2017 - Jul 2020

This bachelor's degree at the University of Utrecht is one of the most interdisciplinary Al bachelors available. Besides math, computer science, algorithmics and so forth, this bachelor's degree also teaches courses related to neuroscience and philosophy. It provided me with many technical skills as well as unique insights to succeed in an everchanging world.



# **PROFILE**

Versatile software and AI engineer, with strong research skills. Quick learner, adaptable and thrives in new environments. I enjoy creating and working on complex projects and bringing them from development into production. This also pairs well with my eagerness to grow as a software developer as there is always something new to learn. My academic background helps me to implement complex algorithms and systems, as well as developing and training various AI models.

#### CONTACT

- simon.mariani65@amail.com
- linkedin.com/in/simon-mariani65
- +31 6 375 552 91

# **LANGUAGES**

- Dutch fluent
- English fluent
- Spanish intermediate
- German intermediate
- Chinese elementary

# PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- Python
- JavaScript
- HTML/CSS
- C#
- R
- C C++
- Clingo Prolog Netlogo

#### FRAMEWORKS AND SOFTWARE

- Django Flask FastAPI
- NodeJS ExpressJS
- ReactJS
- SQL NoSQL
- PyTorch CUDA
- Linux
- Unity
- PowerBl

#### **DEVELOPMENT TOOLS**

- Docker Docker Compose Docker Swarm
- Kubernetes
- Git GitHub GitHub Actions
- Azure AWS
- ETL/ELT

# **PUBLICATIONS AND RESEARCH**

# Master's Thesis AI (UvA)

I wrote my master's thesis at ViNotion about the **uncertainty estimation in neural networks**. Predictions of a neural network cannot be trusted blindly, and some **measure of uncertainty** must be given to their predictions. I did an extensive literature study and wrote a code base for my experiments which is publicly available on my <u>GitHub account</u>. The full paper can be found <u>here</u>.

# Reproducibility Study (UvA)

One way to verify the validity of a study is to look at the **degree of reproducibility**. With a team of students, we re-implemented the code base of an existing paper, and then **validated and extended** their work. The result can be found <a href="https://example.com/here">here</a>.

#### Bachelor's Thesis (UU)

In my bachelor's thesis about **AI to profile serial killers**, I apply and compare several **machine learning** approaches on an **existing database** from the Serial Homicide Expertise and Information Sharing Collaborative (SHEISC). The work can be found in the UU <u>database</u>.

# AI EXPERIENCE

- Deep Learning
- (Distributed) Machine Learning
- (Generative) Computer Vision
- Image Segmentation
- (Generative) Natural Language Processing
- Reinforcement Learning
- Active Learning
- OOD-detection
- Anomaly Detection
- Time Series Analysis
- Recommender systems
- Game Theory